designcuts.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy Policy - Design Cuts

Our Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect and use the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site. When you visit our Web site you may provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis and Web site use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our Web site.

### What information do we collect?

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey or fill out a form.

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name or e-mail address. You may, however, visit our site anonymously.

### What do we use your information for?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalise your experience  
(your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)
  * To improve our website  
(we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)
  * To improve customer service  
(your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)
  * To process transactions  
Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
  * To send periodic emails  
The email address you provide for order processing, may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

### How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information.

All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via TLS v1.2 technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorised with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

We do not store any credit or debit card details on any of our systems.

### Do we use cookies?

Yes (Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognise your browser and capture and remember certain information.

We use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart and understand and save your preferences for future visits. For more information about our use of cookies please read our [cookies policy](https://www.designcuts.com/cookie-policy/).

### Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

To operate effectively as a business, we may need to pass your information on to selected and trusted third-parties. The third-parties we may share information with are:

  *     * Google (for gathering website analytics)
    * Facebook (for targeted advertising)
    * Active Campaign (for email newsletter usage)
    * Vanilla (for notification emails from our forum)
    * MessengerPeople (for WhatsApp updates)

In addition, any third-party to whom we may need to disclose personal information in order to comply with our legal, regulatory and statutory obligations. This may be as part of a legal process, (for example, in response to a court order or in response to a law enforcement agency’s request, or where they believe it’s necessary). This could be to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or situations involving potential threats to the physical safety, property or rights of any person. It could also include non-compliance with our website rules, or as otherwise permitted or any third-party where you’ve given your consent.

Please be assured that when we outsource any processes we ensure that any supplier or contractor has adequate security measures in place. We’ll also require them to comply with privacy principles as part of our contract with them.

### Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Our website is not directed at children under 16, and we won’t knowingly allow anyone under 16 to provide us any personally identifying information; if you’re under 16, please don’t provide any information about yourself on this website. In the event that we learn we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 16, we will delete that information from our database as quickly as possible.

### HOW TO ACCESS, CORRECT YOUR INFORMATION & WITHDRAW CONSENT

You’re able to correct the information we hold about you as follows:

If you’re a design Cuts customer, you can use our [contact form here](https://www.designcuts.com/contact/) to send in new details.

You’re able to change your preferences relating to marketing communications from design Cuts and withdraw your consent at any time, as follows:

Filling in our [contact form here](https://www.designcuts.com/contact/).

You may make a request to access your personally identifiable information that’s held by us and maintained in our database. To do this you need to send in your request via our [contact form here](https://www.designcuts.com/contact/).

From 25 May 2018, depending on the circumstances, you may also have the right to:

request erasure of personal information we hold about you, request restriction of processing of such information, object to the processing of such information, request a copy of such information in a portable format.

If you have concerns about the way we handle your personal data, you can contact the [Information Commissioners Office](https://www.ico.org.uk/concerns/) or raise a complaint.

### Contact Us

You can contact us at the following address:

Design Cuts  
244 STATION ROAD  
ADDLESTONE  
WEYBRIDGE  
KT15 2PS  
Tel. 01932 268 809  
(Please note Design Cuts do not use agencies for recruitment and do not require any third party help for any recruitment we undertake. If you require support or have a query, please [contact us here](https://www.designcuts.com/contact/).)

### Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our websites privacy policy

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

This policy was last reviewed/modified on March 27th 2018.
